How we doing? Um, real quick before have
some questions about the players. I
think just on behalf of both of us, like
we just want to thank the respective
staff for the work that they put in, the
coaching staff, the scouting staff, the
football operations staff, people that
are involved in the process. I mean, we
wouldn't say it was seamless, but it's
pretty seamless. and just the knowledge,
the preparedness, the communication like
it's we operate and function as a unit
and that's how we built the program and
everything we do is about the team and
there's no better example of that than
the draft and the weekend and the
process they went through. So, you know,
on behalf of both of us, you know, we we
were able to do this without the staffs.
So, they're as big a part of this as
anybody and uh you know, they're a big
reason why we're you know, in the
position that we're in. So, you know, if
you guys want to just go ahead and just
start with some questions and then kind
of go through the day and and go from
there.
>> Um, how good do you feel about being
able to get a player of McDonald's uh
caliber in the second round?
>> McDonald is a guy we all we all like
scouts, coaches, everybody, collective
group, everybody like the talent. Uh,
young player, but he's he's grown. He
shows the strength, you know, in the run
game. He shows the ability to get off
blocks and finish. So very excited to
add a young defensive tackle to that
room and he only, you know, I know he'll
flourish with the guys that he'll be
learning from.
>> Both sides of the football, you always
want to build in the trenches and be
strong in there line of scrimmage. With
the first two picks, how much do you
feel like you'll have really competitive
practices when those guys lock up and
with your bets adding to that mix?
>> Yeah, we've added some really talented
guys that are competitors. They are
physical uh guys. So, we know it's going
to we've improved our team today and
that's what you want to do in the draft.
You want to improve your roster with a
ton of competitive guys and that's what
we did today. So, I'm excited to see
these guys get here uh get assimilated
to how we do things and see them go out
and compete. So, it'll be it'll be fun.
>> You often talk about guys that do it the
right way. You love football. Other
things outside
of their physical ability seems like a
little bit of interaction. We had got a
group of those that
>> Yeah, they're they're all, as you guys
probably have noticed, they're all our
type of guys. They're they're football
first guys, high character guys, guys
who just love playing football guys, big
smiles, big energy guys just, you know,
they're going to fit right into our
locker room, right? And not just the
person, but we feel like we got really
good football players as well. It always
starts with the film first and having
great character, great men on top of
that makes it even better and we got
that in all the guys that we chosen.
>> You uh mentioned that last night there
were guys that that you all wanted to
draft at 91 that you felt were going to
be discussed at 106. Were you able to
get those guys? Yeah, I mean really the
first two picks um of the day um if
FabetHei and Woodz um you know Fabi, you
know, we kind of sat there and picked at
106. We felt that was the best thing.
You started to actually see a little bit
of a run on the offensive line there at
the top of the round. Um and then
Woodazz was a player where we kind of
just moved back there a few spots and we
felt like just going back a few grab a
pick, we'd still be able to get him at
123 or wherever we ended up picking him.
But I mean to do's point talking about
some of the earlier players those were
two players that we had conviction like
collectively coaching staff kind of had
a vision and a role for them. Frank
relative to Woodazz also had a vision in
a role. So when you combine the two
that's why we talk through all these
scenarios and all these situations
because we're trying to fit play get the
players here that fit what we're doing
and that the coaches and the staff have
a vision for the player. We're never
going to you know square peg a round
hole a player regardless of what
somebody might think. in the end, we'll
talk about it. If it makes sense, then
we'll try to make it work. But
obviously, those two players were
examples of players we were talking
about yesterday that happened to be
available today and we were able to add
them to the team today.
>> And I saw the camera caught you.
What did you like about
>> I'm pumping my fist on every on every
The camera? The camera just The camera
only got that one. Come on, Omar. We
missed out on all the good stuff. Good
action. No, that's the only one you saw.
Well, that reaction was for each and
every pick. I'm I love them all. No, no.
Fetchy. Uh but like to play a very smart
player. Uh can play multiple positions.
He play guard, plays some center. So
having that flexibility at at the
interior of our offensive line is uh
you're excited about when you get a guy
that had been a ball like him. He talked
about good line about almost feel like
you're feel like you're starving, like
you're that hungry. What did you see
from him just in terms of mental makeup
having had to earn it all the way out of
high school now?
>> Yeah, really good. I mean, you know, not
necessarily transfer up and kind of
transfer up. Kind of started at one
program and then elevated to another
program, but his mentality, his
leadership, just his overall presence. I
mean, he's a great kid. He's very smart.
Takes coaching. Um, and you kind of look
at his story and his journey, like he's
made himself into the player that he is.
And then our job is to make him a better
player relative to where he is right
now. So, um, great human being. Like we
had him in the building. Um, has some
leadership qualities, has some
toughness. I mean, he's sturdy as hell.
He's thick. He's really, really strong.
Um, so he's got the right makeup and the
right mindset and he's just got a good
spirit about him.
>> Hey Nick, you um I know this is just the
beginning, right? You just the draft is
the beginning, but all the work that
goes into it and being able to have your
board or your kind of wish list getting
what you want. Can you talk about what
that feels like to be taking the next
step as you move forward?
>> Yeah, I mean when you go into this you
kind of have I mean we both kind of have
like a list of players and then we kind
of match it up and say hey if we have
the opportunity to add these players to
our team then you know it'd be great for
the overall organization and what we're
trying to do and we were able to do that
here today but I mean this is one
snapshot so now we'll kind of pivot and
kind of take inventory. All right,
here's where we are today. probably some
things that'll happen here this
afternoon after the draft work through
on drafted for agency and then there's
still another grouping of players that's
out there it's available so we'll kind
of evaluate our team where are we can we
upgrade some spots even if we have a
player there currently maybe we replace
them with another option so I mean it's
pretty fluid here I mean this is I mean
obviously there's a lot of work and time
that goes into this from everybody um
but by the same token we're in the
offseason program we're kind of in phase
one we're going to eventually transition
to phase two where the players will
actually get on the field with the staff
and then we'll kind of keep track of
kind of what's going on leaguewide.
There'll probably be some attrition from
the draft players that were drafted
probably created spots or other
opportunities where players kind of get
knocked out and then we'll look to see
if there's somebody out there that makes
sense for us
by the time that you
get the scouting team. How much studying
do you have to put into especially with
the amount of players that there is in
the draft also at the same time getting
prepared for the next season?
>> Yeah, there is no offseason. It turn it
turns right into you know draft
preparation uh really starting at the
combine. So it was really really cool. I
think one of the first interviews I had
at the combine was was Marlin and that
that was a really cool moment for us to
be able to get him. Really like the tape
from my initial watch of him and to be
able to get him. So it's a it's an
ongoing process. I tell my my studying
never stops. Like I'm still watching
guys today trying to make sure you know
we're correct on the guys that we're
taking and we all like the guys. So that
process never ends up until we have to
take the pick. So uh it's been a
thorough process, but my process is sped
up by the staff like our scouting
department. They lay so much groundwork
that I get a head start when I do begin
to watch guys. I know who to watch. I
know what areas to look for. So they do
an outstanding job of prepping me for
that. And then you go in and you have
draft some players that come
at that position. How exciting is it for
you as a former player and as a coach
to, you know, get excited about getting
ready to watch that type of competition.
>> Yeah, football is all about competition.
Look, and that's what you add these
young guys to. We already have a really
good team and we had the opportunity,
you know, over the past couple days to
add some really talented young men that
are going to come in and compete. Man,
competition only makes everyone better.
And that's what we're going to see.
We're going to see our football team
improve once these guys get on the field
because they have to raise their level
of play to go and earn a spot. And
that's what you that's what we're going
to love see. We're going to have some
really good battles in training camp and
I can't wait to watch them.
>> Nick, when it comes to Lewis Bond, what
did you hear from the Boston College
staff from Bill O'Brien just
on him?
>> Yeah, really smart, very instinctive,
good ball skills. um kind of finds a way
to get open, very productive with his
opportunities. I know that was a player
that coach McDaniels spent time with in
the spring on the Zoom and he said it
was one of the smartest players that he
ever talked to as a part of this
process. So, and you see that in his
play, very dependable. He's in the right
spot. Um good football player. I would
say he he has football player traits.
You might look at the card of
measurables and say, "Well, he's a
little slower, a little shorter, but he
produced consecutively for multiple
years." So obviously played in kind of
an NFL style offense and coach O'Brien's
system. So some of the things will carry
over. Some of the things will be a
little bit different, but you saw a lot
of good things on tape and that was a
player like as we kind of worked through
today on Saturday, we were talking and
hey, what do you think? Yeah, we like we
both liked the player. Ben liked the
player. So all right, if we have an
opportunity to add him to the team,
let's figure it out, which is why we
made the pick we did there in the sixth
round. They came to me because
this is sort of like Christmas for y'all
today. You know, they you got your
presents under the tree. You pull them
out, but now you started, you know,
taking them out, starting to play with
them. Now, when does it start to see how
the shine comes out, comes on like, you
know, how does it go move? Just talk
about moving from here.
>> Yeah. Moving forward in uh next in two
weeks, we'll have our rookie mini camp.
Most of the guys will be able to come in
and participate. We see the guys on the
field and that's the exciting time to
see guys actually out working with
coaches. You know, we get co coaches we
get really fired up about that first
watch that first opportunity to get the
guys in the Texans uniform to get them
on the grass. So, you know, we're
excited about it. You know, you've
watched the tape. You spent a lot of
time, you know, getting to know these
guys and our coaches have built already
built really great relationships with
these guys by zooming them 30 visits.
So, it's uh be more even more exciting
once we hit the grass and we can get
done with this.
that evolution from a philosophy
regards.
>> And look, Kaden is a great football
player and for me, you know, we've had
success with smaller defensive linemen.
That doesn't necessarily mean that that
was what we were looking for all the
time. Like we just we had I've worked
with some really good coaches who were
able to get the best out of players and
the traits that they possess. Those
smaller guys, explosive traits, they
were able to knock back. And we've seen
where we've, you know, you start to lose
some in the run game. So you get a guy
like Kaden who's not only just a big
body, but he is an explosive guy. He has
the twist, he has the explosiveness, and
he's stout versus the run. Like that's a
a bonafide defensive tackle that's going
to impact our defense in a in a major
way.
>> Thank you.
>> You want to ask about the coal
underneath my tree that I open in my
presence?
Appreciate you